You will travel far, my little Kal-EI.
你将到很远的地方去，我的小凯尔
But we will never leave you...
但我们永远不会离开你
...even in the face of our deaths.
就算死亡已近在我们眼前
You will make my strength your own.
我会把我的力量给你
You will see my life through your eyes...
你会透过你的眼睛看见我的一生
...as your life will be seen through mine.
如同我会透过我的眼睛看见你的一生
The son becomes the father, and the father the son.
儿子变成了父亲，父亲又变成了儿子
In spite of your past...
不管你的过去如何
...I know you're a good man.
我知道你是个好人
And all good men...
所有的好人
...deserve a second chance.
都有重新来过的机会
From the moment I received your first letter...
从我收到你的第一封信起…
...I knew you were not like the rest.
我就知道你和其他人不同
You came from nothing...
你开始什么都没有
...and you worked so hard to get where you are.
经过了极大的努力才达到现在的地位
You might have made a few mistakes.
其间也许犯了一些错误
- Gertrude, for God's sake! - Damn it, Gertrude, let us in now!
- 加图德，看在上帝的份上！ - 见鬼，加图德，让我们进去！
You said that if I helped you get out of prison...
你说过如果我帮你逃出去
...you'd take care of me.
你就会对我很好的
And you have.
而你的确做到了
You've shown me pleasures that I've never known.
你让我感受到前所未有的快乐
That's why you deserve...
所以你将得到…
...everything.
这一切
I love you...
我爱你
...Lex Luthor.
雷克斯・路瑟
Gertrude, let us in. He's a crook.
加图德，让我们进去，他是个骗子
He doesn't love you, Gertrude!
他不爱你呀，加图德！
He's a monster! Gertrude!
他是个坏人！加图德！
- You can keep that. - Oh, God.
- 你留着吧 - 哦，天啊
The rest is mine.
其它的都是我的
We're done.
结束了
Bye, Martha.
再见，玛莎
Oh, Clark.
哦，克拉克
Oh, my boy.
哦，我的孩子
Will you get that thing out of my face!
把那个东西弄走！
Lex, your friends give me the creeps.
雷克斯，你的朋友让我感觉很不舒服
Prison is a creepy place, Kitty.
监狱本来就不是舒服的地方
One needs to make creepy friends in order to survive.
想要活下来的话 你就得跟一些牛鬼蛇神做朋友
Even a man with my vast talents is won'th less inside...
在里面，像我一个这么聪明的脑袋
...than a can'ton of cigarettes and a sharp piece of metal in your pocket.
也不比一条香烟或口袋里一把利器值钱
Do you know the story of Prometheus? No, of course you don't.
你听过普洛米修斯的故事吗 你当然没听过
Prometheus was a god who stole the power of fire from the other gods...
普洛米修斯从其它神那里偷了火的力量
...and gave control of it to mortals.
他把火给了人类
In essence, he gave us technology. He gave us power.
也可以说，他给了我们科技 他给了我们力量
So we're stealing fire? In the Arctic.
所以我们要去北极偷火？
Actually, sort of. You see, whoever controls technology controls the world.
可以这么说 你想想，谁控制了科技谁就控制了世界
The Roman Empire ruled the world because they built roads.
古罗马帝国因为造路而统治世界
The British Empire ruled the world because they built ships.
大英帝国因为造船而统治世界
America, the atom bomb, and so on and so forth.
美国因为原子弹…等等
I just want what Prometheus wanted.
我想要的东西和普洛米修斯一样
Sounds great, Lex, but you're not a god.
听起来很棒，雷克斯 但你不是神
Gods are selfish beings who fly around in little red capes...
神只不过是披着红披风 整天飞来飞去的自私之徒
...and don't share their power with mankind.
而不把他的力量与人类分享
Hey, boss.
嘿，老板
We found something.
我们找到了
No, I don't wanna be a god.
我不想当神
I just wanna bring fire to the people.
我只想把火种带给人类
And I want my cut.
并且，我也要我自己那份
Was this his house?
这是他以前的家吗？
You might think so. Most would.
大部份人都会这么想
This is more of a monument to a long dead...
较正确的说法是
...and extremely powerful civilization.
这是一个非常强大的 远古文明留下来的遗址
This is where he learned who he was.
他在这里得知他的身世
This is where he came for guidance.
当他迷惘时他在这里寻求方向
Possibilities.
可能…
Endless possibilities.
无限的可能
You act like you've been here before.
你看起来好像你来过这里
My son...
我的儿子
...you do not remember me.
你不记得我
I am Jor-EI.
我是佐尔
I'm your father.
我是你的父亲
By now, I will have been dead many thousands of your years.
我已经死了几千年了
- He thinks I'm his son. - You are the only survivor of Krypton.
- 他把我当成他的儿子了 - 你是氪星惟一的幸存者
Embedded in the crystals before you is the total accumulation of all literature...
你前面的这些水晶里储存着
...and scientific fact from dozens of other worlds...
第 28 银河系里
...spanning the 28 known galaxies.
数十个文明发展的所有文学和科学知识
There are questions to be asked.
在这里会提出许多问题
Here in this...
在这个
This Fortress of Solitude...
隐密的堡垒
...we shall try to find the answers together.
我们将共同追寻解答
Can he see us?
他看得到我们吗？
No, he's dead.
不，他已经死了
So, my son...
我的儿子
...Kal-EI...
凯尔
...speak.
问吧
Tell me everything...
告诉我所有的事
...starting with crystals.
从水晶开始
Hey, boy.
乖孩子
- On Tuesday, between support...
周二，在支持者间…
- hindered the firefighting efforts for all those...
消防队员们的奋力扑救…
Police have finally arrived and it's still complete mayhem down here.
警察终于到来 但现场还是一片混乱
Fighting broke out in the southernmost region...
战事在最南边区域打响…
...with border fire and small-arms attacks prevalent.
边境上小规模武器袭击时有发生
Don't worry, I buried it this morning.
别担心，我早上把它埋起来了
- It was futile trying to force him to testify before a grand jury.
想让他在大陪审团面前作证是徒劳的
Mom?
妈妈？
Five years.
五年了
If your father was alive, he never would have let you go.
如果你爸爸还在世 他绝不会让你走的
I almost gave up hope.
我差点放弃了希望
I just thought I would never see you again.
我以为我再也看不到你了
Oh, Clark.
哦，克拉克
Did you find what you were looking for?
你找到你要找的东西了吗？
I thought, hoped...
我曾想过，满怀希望
...it might still be there.
它也许还在那
Your home?
你的家乡？
That place was a graveyard.
那个地方像座坟场
I'm all that's left.
我是唯一的生还者
Clark, the universe is a big place.
克拉克，宇宙是非常浩大的
And you don't know who's out there.
你不知道宇宙里还有谁在
And even if you are the last...
就算你真的是最后一个生存者
...you're not alone.
你也不会孤单的
I know.
我知道
- Sorry. - Look out!
- 不好意思 - 小心！
Watch out, will you?
小心点
- Excuse me. - Sorry.
- 不好意思 - 抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉
Great. Would you be careful?
你能不能小心点？
- Jimmy. - Mr. Clark! I mean, Kent! Mr. Kent!
- 吉米 - 克拉克先生，不，我是说，肯特先生！
Welcome back! Oh, my God!
欢迎回来！ 天啊！
Hey, come... Wait right there. I'll be right back.
跟我… 你在这等着我马上回来
Oh, hey, sorry, guys, I'm still looking for a place to live...
抱歉，各位 我还在找住的地方
...if you know of anything reasonable.
如果你知道
Behind you, Mr. Kent. I made it myself. It's a cake.
在你后面，肯特先生 这个蛋糕是我自己做的
Oh, it looks...
哦
...delicious.
很好吃
Olsen! Where are the photos of that birthday-clown-massacre thing?
欧森！生日派对小丑大屠杀事件的照片呢？
I'm on it, chief. Hey, look who's back.
我正在办，主编 看看谁回来了
- Kent? - Hey, chief.
- 肯特？ - 嘿，主编
- Thank you for giving me my job back. - Don't thank me.
- 谢谢你让我回到这里来上班 - 别谢我
Thank Norm Palmer for dying.
你应该谢诺姆・帕诺死的正是时候
It was his time.
他也寿终正寝了
- Let's get you set up, huh? - Olsen!
- 来帮你整理一下吧 - 欧森！
Okay, so I gotta run...
我该走了
...but I will be back to check on you in a sec, Mr. Kent.
不过我马上就回来，肯特先生
Oh, hey, do you know where I can find Lois?
你知道露意丝在哪吗？
The timing of this automated-ignition countdown...
自动点火前倒计时那段时间
...is the most precarious part of the launch.
是最不稳定的
Lois Lane, Daily Planet.
露意丝・莲恩，星球日报
You also stated that the shuttle will usher in a new era of travel...
你说新的太空梭将带领我们 进入一个新纪元
...enabling the average person to afford transcontinental flights.
连一个普通平民也 付得起星际旅行的费用
But can you tell us the exact price...
你能不能告诉我们一个实际的数字？
...an "average person" will be expected to pay?
人均花费估计是多少？
The answer to that question is in your press packet.
这个问题有不同的答案
The Earth is surrounded by a blanket of air...
地球被一团空气覆盖
...which we call the atmosphere.
我们称之为大气层
It reaches over...
它延伸到…
Yeah. He looks just like his mom.
他看上去就像他的妈妈
Already takes after her too, especially when it comes to getting into trouble.
连行为举止都像 尤其在“闯祸”这方面
Mother?
妈妈？
Oh, yeah, well, I guess you've been gone. Fearless reporter Lois Lane is a mommy.
你离开太久可能不知道 露意丝・莲恩是个妈妈了
Oh, you know, I'll just... I'll take that. That's good.
我只是… 给我吧，很好
- Sorry. - No. She's got plenty.
- 抱歉 - 没关系，反正她很多
- Wait, she's married? - Yes.
- 等等，她结婚了吗？ - 是的
No. Not really. It's more like a prolonged engagement.
也不算是，更像是超长的婚约
But don't ask Miss Lane when they're tying the knot...
不过你可别问她何时结婚
...because she hates that question.
她很讨厌这个问题
- Like this follow the same stringent safety guidelines set by NASA?
就好像要履行国家宇航局 同样的安全条例？
Since this is a joint venture with the Air Force...
既然这是和空军联合的行动…
You all right? You look like you could use a drink.
你还好吗？ 你看起来好像需要去喝一杯
This place is so tacky. Why are we back here?
这个地方真破烂 我们回来这里干吗？
Kitty, while you were doing your nails and ordering fur coats online...
咪咪，当你忙着修你的指甲 和在网上购买貂皮大衣时
...I was busy unlocking the secrets...
我可是在忙着
...of one of the most advanced civilizations in the universe.
解开宇宙最先进文明的秘密
Werert there two of those?
本来不是有两只吗？
You see, unlike our clunky earthbound forms of construction...
你看，比起地球上使用的笨拙建筑方式
...the technology on Krypton, Supermars home world...
氪星，也就是超人的母星
...was based on manipulating the growth of crystals.
利用水晶的生长来建造东西
Sounds like hocus-pocus to me.
听起来像在变魔术
Well, naturally, to the primitive mind, any sufficiently advanced technology...
对我们这些原始的脑袋来说
...would be indistinguishable from magic.
超先进的科技跟变魔术没什么两样
But imagine: Cities, vehicles, weapons...
但想想一下，城市，车辆，武器…
...entire continents...
整个大陆
...all grown.
所有的一切
To think that one could create a new world...
很难想像能从一个这么简单的物体
...with such a simple little object.
创造出一个新世界
It's like a seed.
它就像一个种子
And all it needs is water.
它只需要水
Like...
就像…
...Sea-Monkeys.
海猴
Exactly, Kitty.
没错，咪咪
Like Sea-Monkeys.
就像海猴
Clark has been doing a little soul-searching for the last couple years.
克拉克这几年做了很多心灵之旅
- He saw Ilamas. - Yeah?
- 他见了好几位喇嘛 - 是吗？
- Yeah. - Must be tough coming back.
- 嗯 - 回来对你来说很困难吧？
- Coming back? - To work.
- 回来？ - 回来工作
Yeah.
嗯
Well, you know, things change.
变化了很多
I mean, of course things change...
我是说，事物当然会变化
...but sometimes things that you didn't think would change could change.
但有时候一些你觉得不会变的也变了
Take Lois.
例如露意丝
A woman like her, I never thought she'd settle down.
没想到像她这样的女人会安定下来
You know, if you ask me... Because she'll never tell you this...
如果你问我… 因为她永远不会说这个
...but if you ask me, she's still in love with you-know-who.
但如果你问我 她还在爱着“那个人”
The original space shuttle generated 7.5 million pounds of thrust...
原本的太空梭在发射时
...just in the initial launch phase.
会产生750万磅的推动力
But, by piggybacking on this Boeing 777... Yes?
不过我们把它装载在波音777的背上时…
If this launch is as pivotal as you claim...
如果这次的发射真如你说的那么重要
...why is it being covered by one news network?
为什么只有一家媒体来采访这个消息
Why don't we save those questions for the post-launch briefing.
我们何不把这问题留到发射后的记者会
How about that, Miss Lane?
可以吗，莲恩小姐？
When we hit 40,000 feet, the shuttle will detach, ascend...
当我们到达四万尺时
...and then fire the first of two propellant systems, the liquid fuel boosters.
太空梭会解放第一组的液态推进器
When the shuttle reaches the stratosphere...
当我们到达平流层时
...the secondary insertion booster will fire...
第二组推进器会被点燃
...propelling the craft at 4gs into the mesosphere.
然后以4g的加速度将我们推入中气层
- Careful. - I know.
- 小心 - 我知道
- Careful. Careful.
- 小心，小心
Wow, that's really something, Lex.
哇，真剌激啊，雷克斯
Wait for it.
再等一下
It's freaking Gone With the Wind.
剌激度可媲美《飘》了
- Shut off the camera. - But I'm getting it.
- 把摄影机关了 - 我还在拍摄啊
I said, shut off the damn camera.
我说把摄影机关了
I think I did something wrong.
我好像弄坏了什么
No. That wasrt you.
不，不是你的错
Ignition is at T minus one minute and we are prepping for separation.
1分钟点火倒计时 准备进行梭机分离
CDR, start the clock.
机长，请开始计时
Three minutes and counting.
3分钟倒计时
Body signs normal. Crew is looking good.
主体信号正常 各部分零件正常
Shuttle readouts are holding steady.
太空梭仪表稳定
- We're still a go for launch. - Roger.
- 我们还是要准备发射 - 明白
- Houston, you copy? - Houston, do you copy?
- 休斯敦，收到请回答
Oh, God.
哦，天啊
Electrical variance.
电力不稳
What the...?
到底是…？
Please, there's nothing to worry about.
大家别慌！
It seems that we are experiencing a slight power outage.
看来我们好像有个小小的停电
- What did you do? - It wasrt me. It just cycled back up.
- 你做了什么？ - 什么都没做，只是打开了备用电源
Genesis, radio check from Houston.
“创世纪”，和休士顿确认一下
There we have it. We were experiencing a power outage.
他们确认是短暂的停电
- Climbing to 40,000 feet. - Roger, 40,000 feet.
- 爬升至四万尺 - 收到，四万尺
And it's gone! A blazing fastball...
他得分了！惊人的快球…
Is that it?
停了吗？
I don't think so.
还没呢
Dual engine failure, but they're up and running again.
双引擎失效，但是又恢复运转了
Genesis, I hate to say this, but it looks like we're gonna have to scrub the launch.
“创世纪”，很遗憾 我们必须中止这次发射
- Aborting booster ignition. - Roger. Aborting booster ignition.
- 中止推进器点火 - 收到，中止推进器点火
Boosters are non-responsive. We're still counting down for ignition.
推进器没反应 点火还在倒数计时中
- Platform, we have a problem. - Go.
- 运载机，我们有麻烦了 - 请讲
Looks like something faulted during the power outage.
看来跳电时什么东西坏了
Both boosters are counting down for ignition.
两组推进器都还在倒数计时中
Platform, you have 30 seconds.
运载机，还有30秒
- What? - Release couplings.
- 什么？ - 解除连接器
We can 't shut down boosters.
我们无法关掉推进器
We should be able to manage the launch and recover to the emergency field.
太空梭可以自行发射然后紧急迫降
T minus 23 seconds to ignition.
倒数23妙
Genesis, you're a go for evac procedures.
“创世纪”，允进启动紧急疏散程序
Twenty-one, 20...
21，20
...19...
…19
Couplings are non-responsive.
连接器没有反应
- We're still attached. - Seventeen.
- 我们还连在上面 - 17
- Platform, couplings are jammed. - Fifteen.
- 连接器也卡死了 - 15
Fourteen.
…14
Don't be alarmed. It's absolutely normal.
不用紧张，这是正常的
We're still attached. Couplings are non-responsive.
还是解不开，连接器无反应
- Nine, eight... - Houston, can you do a remote override?
- 9，8… - 休斯敦，你能从远端解除吗？
...seven...
…7
- Remote override is unresponsive. ...six, five...
- 远端解除无效 - …6，5
- I repeat, remote override is unresponsive. ...four, three...
- 重复一遍，远端解除无效 - …4，3…
And if you're lucky, you may hear the faint pop of the sonic boom.
运气好的话还可以听到小声的音爆喔
- Houston, we have ignition. - Roger, ignition.
- 休斯敦，点火成功 - 收到
- This is Python 21, she's pulling away. - Okay, all flight control is on the...
- 这是蟒蛇21号，太空梭快速远去 - 飞行控制启动中…
This is not a drill. Clear nonessential personnel.
这不是演习，疏散无关人员
Switch to emergency band frequencies.
启动紧急应对方案
Warning, warning.
警告，警告
Oh, no! Oh, no!
不！不！
Can I get a little help?
谁来帮帮我？
This is UPV breaking news. From Washington, Frank Jacobs.
这里是华盛顿UPV电台的即时新闻
We've just received word...
我们刚得到消息
...that the inaugural flight of the Genesis space shuttle...
“创世纪”太空梭在空中遇到问题
...is experiencing a midair emergency.
…半空中遇到紧急情况
- A problem with the launch of the new orbital shuttle, Genesis.
新一代“创世纪”发射遭遇问题
The reports are telling us the shuttle failed to disengage...
消息来源指出创世纪未能和777解开
...sending both crafts rocketing towards space.
导致二机一起冲向太空
We're now going live to Cape Canaveral for the latest update on this story.
现在将镜头转回卡纳维尔角… 关注最新动向
Jim, all we know right now...
吉姆，我们现在只知道
...is that the couplings which hold the shuttle to the 777...
777出现故障
...malfunctioned and did not release as planned.
机梭未按计划分离
- We're uncertain... - I should do...
- 我们还不确定… - 我应该…
...why the ignition sequence continued and boosters fired.
…为何点火程序继续推进器发射
However, there's speculation here that the blackout, which...
然而，停电导致很大问题…
Help me sit up.
扶我坐起来
Mach one. Still tied to the shuttle at 42,000 feet.
火狐1号仍连接在太空梭上 已爬升至42000尺
- Houston, we need some help. Houston! - Running diagnostics check. Stand by.
- 休斯敦，我们请求支援！ - 准备运行故障诊断程序
Insertion booster ignition in five seconds.
“入轨推进器”点火5秒倒计时
Warning, warning.
警告，警告
What the hell is that?
那到底是什么？
There's some kind of unidentified bogey coming from the north.
有不知名的敌机从北面过来
- Roger that. - And it's coming in fast.
- 了解 - 而且以超快的速度
Declaring an emergency.
紧急情况
Overspeed, overspeed.
超速，超速
Altitude...
高度…
Do you see that?
看到了吗？
Fly up, fly up.
上升，上升
Is everyone all right?
大家都没事吧
Are you okay?
你没事吧
Well, I hope this experience hasn't put any of you off flying.
那么我希望大家不要因此次事件 而害怕飞行
Statistically speaking, it's still the safest way to travel.
因为数据上来说 飞行还是最安全的
Superman! Superman! Superman!
超人！超人！超人！
Superman!
超人！
Okay, everybody, listen up.
大家听好了
I wanna know it all, everything.
我要知道所有的事情
Olsen, I wanna see photos of him everywhere. No, I want the photos.
欧森，我要他的照片占满所有版面 不，我要看到他的“独家”照片
Sports, how are they gonna get that plane out of the stadium?
体育版，他们如何把飞机运出场外？
Travel, where did he go? Was he on vacation? If so, where?
旅游版，他之前去哪了？ 渡假吗？在哪里？
Gossip, has he met somebody? Fashion, is that a new suit?
八卦版，他有新恋情吗？ 时尚版，他穿的超人服是新的吗？
Health, has he gained weight? What's he been eating?
健康版，他增重了吗？ 他都吃些什么？
Business, how is this gonna affect the stock market? Long-term, short-term.
商务版，这对股市有什么影响？ 短期或长期
Politics, does he still stand for truth, justice, all that stuff? Lifestyle:
政治版，他还是正义和事实的代表吗 生活版
"Superman Returns."
“超人归来”
Come on.
快去吧
Gil, how many F's in "catastrophic"?
吉伯 “灾难性”这个字里有几个“f”
None. What's the usage?
一个都没有，如何使用？
"This mysterious electromagnetic pulse knocked out portable devices...
神秘的电磁波让所有的电子产品及 便携设备失效
...and entire power grids, causing a catastrophic event during..."
导致一连串灾难性的…
- Lois! - Yes.
- 露意丝！ - 是
In my office.
到我办公室来
This goes for everyone.
大家也都听好了
The story isn't the blackout, it's Superman!
这次的新闻不是大停电，而是超人！
The story is the EMP, chief.
主编，电磁波事件才是真正的新闻
Every electronic device on the East Coast goes dark.
东岸所有的电子仪器都在瞬间失效
- First, are you okay? - Yes, thank you.
- 首先，你没事吧 - 没事，谢谢
Lois, three things sell papers: Tragedy, sex and Superman.
露意丝，好卖的报纸有三要素： 惨案，性，还有超人
People are sick of tragedy, we know you can't write won'th a damn about sex.
人们对灾难已快失去兴趣了 你对性爱又一窍不通
That means one thing. That one thing is Superman. And you know it, Lois.
所以剩下来的只剩超人了
Lois?
露意丝？
- Are you all right? You sure? - Yeah.
- 你没事吧 - 嗯
- Yeah, I'm fine. - Thank God.
- 我没事 - 谢天谢地
- Where's Jason? - I don 't know. Isn 't he with you?
- 杰森呢？ - 他不是跟你在一起吗？
- No. - Well, where is he?
- 没有 - 他人呢？
Hi.
嗨
Hello.
你好
Who are you?
你是谁
I'm Clark Kent, an old friend of your mom's from before you were born.
我是克拉克・肯特 我在你还没出生时就和你妈妈是朋友了
Really? She never mentioned you.
是吗？她从来没提过你
Really? Never?
真的吗？从没？
- No. - Jason.
- 从没 - 杰森
- What are you doing here, honey? - Daddy's office is boring.
- 你在这里做什么，宝贝？ - 爸爸的办公室好无聊
Daddy's office is boring?
爸爸的办公室好无聊？
Clark, hey! Welcome back.
克拉克，嗨，欢迎回来
- I see you've already met the munchkin. - Yeah, we were just talking...
- 你已经见过我儿子了 - 对啊，我们正在聊天
- Did you take vitamins? Eye drops? - Yes. Yes.
- 你吃维生素了吗，点眼药了吗？ - 吃了，点了
- Albuterol? Poly-Vi-Flor? - Yes. Yes, Mom.
- 气喘药呢？波利拜弗呢？ - 都吃了，妈妈
Good boy. He's a little fragile, but he's gonna grow up...
乖孩子，他现在身体不太好 但他长大以后…
...to be big and strong like his dad, won't you?
一定会长得跟他爸爸一样高大强壮，是吧
- Yes? - Yes.
- 是吗？ - 是的
Oh, I saw you on the...
我看见你在那飞机…
Oh, yeah. That was nothing.
哦，那没什么
- Hey, can I borrow your stapler? - Oh, yeah.
- 你的订书机能借我吗？ - 当然
Thanks.
谢谢
Congratulations on the Pulitzer. That's incredible.
恭喜你得到普利兹奖，真不可思议
Yeah. Can you believe it? It's...
对呀，难以相信
So I wanna hear all about your trip.
对了，你的旅行如何？
Where did you go? What did you see? Meet anyone special?
你去了哪里？看到什么？ 认识了什么人吗？
Well, there's so much. Where to begin?
太多了，我不知从何说起
Where's the little guy? Hey, kiddo.
那小子呢？ 嘿，小子
- How are you? - Good.
- 你好吗？ - 很好
Can you work some magic to get your uncle...
你能不能向你的叔叔拉点亲戚关系
...to stop giving me such a hard time on this article?
让他不要一直为难我这篇报导？
- Please? - Again?
- 行吗？ - 又一次？
- Again. - You got it.
- 又一次 - 没问题
- How are you, kiddo? - Good.
- 你好吗，孩子？ - 好
Oh, this is Clark.
哦，这是克拉克
- Clark, Richard. Richard, Clark. - Richard White.
- 克拉克，理查；理查，克拉克 - 理查・怀特
Hi.
嗨
Richard's an assistant editor here who's basically saved our International section.
理查是这里的副编辑 他一手拯救了我们的国际版
He's also a pilot and he loves horror movies.
他也是个飞行员 喜欢看恐怖电影
Clark is...
克拉克是…
Well, he's Clark.
他就是克拉克
Well, it's great to finally meet you. I've heard so much.
真高兴终于见到你 我听说了很多你的事
- Oh, you have? - Yeah, Jimmy won't shut up about you.
- 是吗？ - 是啊，吉米这小子一直说到你
- Gotta run. - Where?
- 该走了 - 去哪？
You heard Perry. Supermars back, and he thinks I'm the only one equipped to...
你听到啦，派瑞说超人回来了 而我是唯一能…
To what?
能什么？
- I don't know, you know. - So don't listen to him.
- 不知道 - 那就别理他
I'm not. Going to the power plant to check out the blackout.
我是不理啊 我现在要去发电厂调查停电
Okay.
好吧
- Bye, Mom. - Bye.
- 妈妈再见 - 再见
- Bye, Lois. - And she's gone.
- 再见，露意丝 - 她走了
No matter how close we are, that woman will always be a mystery.
不管我们有多亲近 对我来说那女人一直是个谜
If you need anything, I'm right over there.
需要什么的话 我的办公室在那里
Nice to finally meet you.
很高兴见到你
Where do you wanna go? Wanna go to the park?
你要去哪？去公园吗？
And he's got the whole world In his hands
#整个世界，在他手中
He's got the whole world
#整个世界…
Oh, he's cute.
他蛮可爱的嘛
Run into trouble?
碰上麻烦吗？
- Should see the other guy. - What are we gonna do?
- 你应该问对方 - 我们接下来做什么？
Modify it, attach it to the stern.
你们把它改造后装在船尾
I don't care if the instructions are Russian.
我不管说明书是不是俄文写成的
- Lois? - Hey, Clark.
- 露意丝 - 克拉克
How does it feel to be back at work?
回来工作的感觉怎样？
Pretty good. You know, kind of like riding a bike, I guess.
蛮不错呀，就像骑脚踏车吧
- A bike? - Yeah, you know...
- 脚踏车？ - 对呀，嗯…
Never mind.
算了
But I was wondering...
我在想…
...since I've gotten back, we haven't really had a chance to catch up.
我回来后我们还没有聚在一起聊聊
I thought maybe, if you'd like, we could go grab some food...
如果你不介意的话 我们可以去吃个饭
- Hey, can I ask you something? - Sure.
- 我可以问你一件事吗？ - 当然
Have you ever met someone and it's like you're from different worlds...
你认识了某人 你们感觉像是两个不同世界的人
...but you shared such a connection you knew you were destined to be together?
但你们之间却燃起了强烈的爱情火花 你知道你们是注定要在一起的
Then he just takes off without explaining why...
但他突然间就离开了
...or without even saying goodbye?
连一点解释或一句再见都没说
Sounds cheesy, I know.
蛮低级的吧
- Well, maybe... - Taxi!
- 不过，也许… - 计程车！
...it was hard to say goodbye because he had to go...
说再见对他来说太困难了
...and he wanted to say goodbye, but maybe it was too difficult for him.
也许他想说，但说不出口
Difficult? What's so difficult about it? "Goodbye." It's easy.
困难？有什么好困难的 “再见”，很简单啊
What's so hard about saying goodbye?
说再见有什么困难？
Who are we talking about?
我们到底在说谁呀？
Nobody, just forget I said anything.
没说谁，当我没说过吧
Taxi! Hey!
计程车！嘿！
Taxi!
计程车！
Wow, thanks.
哇，谢谢
312 Riverside Drive, please.
河滨路312号，谢谢
Good night, Clark.
晚安，克拉克
Superman!
超人！
I want egg rolls.
我要蛋卷
Nice try, kiddo. Only steamed chicken and snow peas for you.
没办法，小子 你只能吃鸡块和雪豆
Why do we order Chinese if he's allergic?
你明知他会过敏为何还要叫中餐外卖？
Because he loves the peas...
因为他喜欢雪豆
...and I think we all prefer egg rolls over macrobiotic shakes.
与微机生物制成的奶昔比起来 我们也比较喜欢吃蛋卷吧
It's a good point.
那倒也是
So I noticed you've been acting a little different lately.
我发现你最近举动怪怪的
Have I?
是吗？
You know, Lois, that article that you wrote.
露意丝，你写的那篇文章
"Why the World Doesrt Need Superman"?
《为何这世界不需要超人》？
No, no, no. No, the other one, from years ago, before we met.
不不不，另一篇 在我们认识前写的
Which article? I wrote dozens about him. I was practically his press agent.
哪一篇啊，我写了好多篇 我就是他的新闻发言人
"I Spent the Night With Superman."
《我和超人共渡良宵》
Richard, come on.
理查，算了
It was the title of an interview.
那只不过是文章的标题
Plus, it was your Uncle Perry's idea.
而且那还是你叔叔派瑞的主意
- No, I know, I know. It's okay, it's okay. - Richard.
- 我知道，我知道，没关系 - 理查
It was a long time ago.
那是很久以前的事了
Were you in love with him?
你那时爱着他吗？
He was Superman. Everyone was in love with him.
他是超人呀，所有人都爱他
But were you?
那你呢？
No.
不爱
Lois, I shouldn 't have brought it up.
露意丝，我不该提这个的
Even though you've been raised as a human being...
虽然你被当成人类抚养长大
...you are not one of them.
你毕竟不是人类
They can be a great people, Kal-EI. They wish to be.
他们可以成为也渴望成为伟大的人，凯尔
They only lack the light to show the way.
他们缺少的是一道照亮道路的光
For this reason above all, their capacity for good...
因为这个原因
...I have sent them you...
我把你，我唯一的儿子
...my only son.
给了他们
Load them up.
把货装上去
Holy sh...
妈的…
Attention, the Metropolis Museum of Natural History...
注意，大都会博物馆
...will be closing in 10 minutes. We hope that you've...
将在十分钟后关门
Sir, we're closing in 10 minutes.
我们再过十分钟就关了
We only need five.
我们只需要五分钟
You're done, the museum's closed. Thank you.
你们该走了，博物馆关门了，谢谢
Are you all right, miss?
你还好吧，小姐？
- My heart. L... l... - I'm sorry?
- 我的心脏… - 什么？
I have a palpitation, a heart palpitation. And a murmur.
我有心悸，还有心杂音
Please, take me to the hospital.
请你带我去医院
Take me to the hospital.
带我去医院
Just hold on tight.
抓紧了
Bingo.
搞定
- There you are, ma'am. - My heart.
- 到了，女士 - 我的心脏
My palpitations, they're gone. What did you do?
我的心悸停止了 你做了什么？
I didn't do anything.
我什么也没做
Call me Katherine.
叫我凯瑟琳
Katherine. I'm glad you're feeling better.
凯瑟琳，很高兴你没事了
- You have places to go, people to save? - Yes.
- 你还得去很多地方，救很多人？ - 对
Would you like to get a cup of coffee sometime?
你要不要一起喝杯咖啡…
- I know that's forward. Or a drink? - Good night.
- 我知道这太直接了点，酒怎么样？ - 晚安，凯瑟琳
Good night.
晚安
It's like this on every channel.
好像每个频道都是这个
He was in Manila at 10:55 p.m. And then spotted...
他晚上10:55出现在马尼拉 然后又…
- Hey, Kent, chief wants to see you. - Oh, thanks.
- 肯特，主编在等你 - 谢谢
But as this security footage from a simple deli robbery proves...
熟食店抢劫的保安录像证明
...there's really no feat too big or too small for the Man of Steel.
…恰好是超人
Reports are flooding in from Metropolis, Houston, Gotham and as far...
洪水般的报道淹没了休斯敦和纽约
Satellites have proven most ineffective at tracking him.
卫星对于追踪他最没用
He might literally be moving near the speed of light.
他移动速度接近光速
- Our map is illuminated with sightings... - Kent!
- 我们的地图上到处是光点 - 肯特！
- The chief is waiting. ...on every continent, giving citizens...
- 主编在等你 - …在每个大陆上，让市民…
These are iconic, and they were taken by a 12-year-old with a camera phone.
这些照片很有象征性 而且是一个十二岁的小孩用手机拍的
- What do you got, Olsen? - I got those.
- 你拍到些什么，欧森？ - 我拍到这些
- Look, in the sky, chief. - It's a bird.
- 看天空的部分，主编 - 那是鸟
- It's a plane. - No, look, it's...
- 那是飞机 - 不，看，那是…
You wanted to see me?
你们在找我吗？
Yeah, Kent, come on in. Sit down.
肯特，进来坐下
I wanna talk a little strategy. Okay.
我想讨论一下策略问题
First off, Lois, I don't understand what you're doing...
首先，露意丝 我不懂你为何
...sneaking around covering the blackout. - It wasrt just a blackout.
- 紧追着停电的报导不放 - 那不是普通的停电
Cell phones, pagers, automobiles, airplane...
手机、传呼机、汽车、飞机…
Every other paper in town has got a female reporter...
其它的报社都至少有一位女记者
...a good-Iooking female reporter, stashed on the roof covering Superman.
漂亮的女记者在屋顶做超人的报导
- And you two are the ones with history. - Chief, I've done Superman.
- 而你是唯一和超人有一段历史的 - 我已经做过超人了
Covered him. You know what I mean.
报道他，你们明白什么意思
Yeah, that makes you an expert. Do him again.
没错，所以你是个专家 你要继续报导他
- There are a dozen other stories out there. - Yeah? Name one.
- 可是还有很多其它的事情可报啊 - 是吗？举个例子
Well, there was a museum robbery last night.
昨天博物馆的抢劫
Even Superman missed that one. He was too busy saving this hooker.
连超人也顾不及那件案子 当时忙着救这个骚货呢
Why don't you guys track down Lex Luthor?
你们为什么不去追查雷克斯・路瑟的下落？
Well, no one's seen him since his fifth appeal.
自从他第五次上诉后就没人再看见过他
He's got more history with Superman than anyone.
而且他跟超人间有数不清的过节
Maybe he's got something to say.
也许他知道些什么
- Luthor's yesterday's news. - No, I like that idea.
- 路瑟是旧闻了 - 不，我觉得这主意不错
Perry, Lex Luthor is a career criminal who nearly killed him, for God's sakes.
派瑞，雷克斯・路瑟是个职业惯犯 他还差点杀死过超人
Jimmy, how did Lex Luthor get out of prison?
吉米 雷克斯路瑟怎么被释放的？
Well, the appeals court called Superman as a witness and he wasrt around.
上诉法庭传超人做证 结果他没出庭
How much do you think that pisses off Superman?
你想超人知道的话会不会气死？
- Give him to someone else. - A lot.
- 把他交给别人吧 - 很生气
- Polly. Give him to Polly.
让波莉去做吧
Lois, Superman.
露意丝，超人
- What about the blackout? - Kent, blackout.
- 那大停电怎么办？ - 肯特，你做大停电
Great. Thanks, chief.
太好了，真谢谢你，主编
Lois, I'm sorry. I'd hate if this damaged our relationship.
露意丝，对不起 我不想这会破坏我们的关系
Relationship?
关系？
- Yeah. - Hi, Mommy.
- 对 - 嗨，妈妈
- Hi, you. - Hey, guys.
- 你好啊 - 大家好
He got an A in science, but a D in gym, so we're doing something right.
他科学拿到了A，体操得了D 至少我们做对了一些
- Yeah, at least one of us is. - What?
- 至少我们之中有一个是对的 - 什么？
It's Perry. He just shoved Superman back into my life.
派瑞，他又把超人推给我了
Well, honey, I'm sure you can find a way to interview Superman...
亲爱的，我相信你能找到办法采访超人
...without bringing him back into your life.
却又不让他再走进你的生活的
There's really no way around it, folks. Superman is back in all of our lives.
无可否认的，超人回来了
We're coming to you from Sydney...
我们在悉尼下城
...where people have gathered on these rooftops to scour the sky...
在商业区的屋顶上为您做实况转播
Okay, how about this? We'll stay late. We'll get dinner.
不如这样吧，我们赶夜工，叫外卖来吃
I'll help with Superman, and you and Clark can work on the blackout together.
我来帮你写超人的报导 你跟克拉克一起写大停电
- Is that all right with you, Clark? - Swell.
- 你觉得如何，克拉克？ - 帅呆了
I was gonna pretend the brakes were out.
我应该是假装煞车失灵
Pretend. Like we talked about.
假装耶，我们之前讨论过的
You didn't actually have to cut them!
你不必真的把煞车线剪断吧！
Of course I did.
我当然需要
A man can always tell when a woman is pretending, especially Superman.
男人一向都知道当女人在装假 尤其是超人
So did you get your rock?
你拿到你的石头了吗？
I did.
拿到了
U.S. Coast Guard issuing a small-craft advisory for the Metropolis ocean area.
全国海岸警卫队提醒小型船只
High-wind advisory is in effect...
风力很大
...ocean currents and tides becoming increasingly dangerous.
潮汐越来越危险
All warnings lasting until later this evening.
所有警报持续到今晚
Security, security.
安全警报
This is U.S. Coast Guard issuing a small-craft advisory for northeast seas.
全国海岸警卫队提醒东北海域小型船只
Winds reaching 50 miles per hour, high tides in the morning.
风速达50英里，今早有巨浪
Waves reaching 20 to 30 feet.
浪高20至30尺
This warning is in effect for all small crafts for the next four hours.
此警告保留4小时
Weird. If these times are right...
奇怪，如果这些时间正确
...the blackout spread from a specific origin point.
那大停电是从一个中心点开始扩散的
Where?
从哪里？
I'm not sure yet.
我还不确定
With the super-hearing, does he hear each sound by itself or everything at once?
他的超级听力是一次听到一个声音 还是听到很多声音？
Both.
都可以
- He's certainly taller than I thought. - 6'4".
- 他比我想像中高多了 - 六尺四
I love that he can see through anything. I'd have fun with that.
我真羡慕他能看穿任何东西 那一定很好玩
Anything but lead.
除了铅以外
- I bet he's... - 225 pounds...
- 我想他一定… - 225磅
...faster than a speeding bullet...
速度快于一颗子弹
...draws his power from the sun, invulnerable to anything but kryptonite...
从太阳汲取能量 除了氪星石外不怕任何东西
...and he never lies. - Kryptonite?
- 从不说谎 - 氪星石？
Radioactive pieces of his home world.
他的母星碎片，含有高量幅射
It's deadly. To him.
那可以杀死他
Lois, how tall would you say Clark is?
露意丝，你说克拉克有多高
About 6'3", 6'4".
六尺三、四
About 200, 215 pounds?
200-215磅？
Jimmy, Jason, let's go get these intrepid reporters something to keep them going.
吉米，杰森，我们去帮这些无畏的记者们 买些晚餐让他们能继续奋斗下去吧
- Burritos! - Come here, canead.
- 要玉米煎饼！ - 过来
We're going this way. Do they have anything other than burritos?
这边来 除了玉米煎饼还有什么？
I think they have fries and burgers.
我想他们有炸鸡块和肉夹饼
So have you found a place to live yet?
你找到地方住了吗？
No. I'm still looking.
我还在找
You know, Lois, I wanted to ask you about that artic...
露意丝，我正好想问你…
Hey, I'm gonna run downstairs for some fresh air. Great!
嘿，我正想下楼透透气 真是的！
Thanks.
谢谢
- Let's talk when I get back. - Sure.
- 等我回来我们再聊吧 - 好吧
You know, you really shouldn't smoke, Miss Lane.
你实在不该吸烟的，莲恩小姐
- Sorry. Didrt mean to startle you. - I'm fine. Really.
- 不好意思，我不是有意吓你 - 我没事，真的
I just wasrt expecting you.
我只是没想到会看到你
With all the press on the plane...
当时机上太多媒体
...I wasrt sure it was the best time for us to talk.
那种情况下不太好说话
Well, there's no press around now. Except for me, of course.
现在没有媒体了 除了我以外
I know people are asking questions now that I'm back.
我回来后，大家都有很多问题
I think it's only fair that I answer those people.
我也有义务回答他们
So you're here for an interview?
所以…你是来接受采访的？
Okay, then.
好吧
- Where did I put that thing? - Right pocket.
- 我把它放哪去了 - 你右边口袋
Let's start with the big question.
我们由最大的问题开始吧
- Where'd you go? - To Krypton.
- 你跑哪去了？ - 氪星
But you told me it was destroyed. Ages ago.
你说过它早就被毁灭掉了
It was.
我是说过
But when astronomers thought they found it...
但有一些太空人以为 他们找到星球的残骸时
...I had to see for myself.
我必须亲自去确认一下
Well, you're back, and everyone seems to be pretty happy about it.
现在你回来了 大家看起来也很高兴
Not everyone.
但不是所有人
- I read the article, Lois. - So did a lot of people.
- 我读过那篇文章，露意丝 - 很多人都读过
- Tomorrow they're giving me the Pulitzer... - Why did you write it?
- 明天他们授予我普利兹奖 - 你为什么要写那篇文章？
How could you leave us like that?
你怎么可以就这样离开我们？
I moved on. So did the rest of us.
我痛过后看开了，大家都看开了
That's why I wrote it.
所以我才写这篇文章
The world doesn't need a savior.
这个世界不需要救世主
And neither do I.
我也不需要
Lois.
露意丝
Will you come with me?
你能跟我来吗?
Why?
为什么?
There's something I wanna show you.
我想让你看一些东西
Please.
来吧
I can't be gone long.
我不能去太久
You won't be.
不会太久的
Clark said the reason you left without saying goodbye...
克拉克说你不告而别…
...is because it was too unbearable for you.
是因为道别对你来说太痛苦了
Personally, I think that's a load of crap.
我觉得那根本就是胡说
- Clark? - He's just a guy I work with.
- 克拉克？ - 是我公司的同事
Maybe Clark's right.
也许克拉克说的没错
You know, my...
你知道，我的…
Richard, he's a pilot. He takes me up all the time.
理查…是个飞行员 他常常带我一起去飞行
Not like this.
不是这样的飞行
I forgot how warm you were.
我忘记你身体有多温暖了
Listen.
仔细听
What do you hear?
你听到了什么？
Nothing.
什么都没有
I hear everything.
我全听到了
You wrote that the world doesn't need a savior...
你写道世界不需要救世主
...but every day I hear people crying for one.
可是每天我都听到人们的呼救
I'm sorry I left you, Lois.
对不起我当时离开你，露意丝
I'll take you back now.
我现在带你回去
Richard's a good man.
理查是个好人
And you've been gone a long time.
而且你又离开那么久
I know.
我知道
L...
我…
So will I see you around?
我还会看到你吗？
I'm always around.
我一直都在
Good night, Lois.
晚安，露意丝
We're having beef, honey. Do you want the tofu wrap or the veggie wrap?
我买了牛肉回来 你要用豆腐皮还是蔬菜皮？
You all right?
你还好吗？
Where have you been?
你去哪了？
I was up on the roof, getting some air.
我…刚才上屋顶去透透气
Tell the truth now.
说实话喔
Were you smoking?
你去抽烟吗？
No.
不是
Is this real?
真的？
- Where'd you find him? - He found me.
- 你怎么找到他的？ - 是他找到我
Oh, this is great. I can't wait to read it.
太棒了，我真等不及要读这篇报导
So, Mr. White, about the blackout...
怀特先生，有关大停电…
Lois, this is the biggest night of your life.
露意丝，今晚是你人生中最重要的夜晚
Have you picked out a dress? Something snazzy?
你选好服装了吗 很高贵的服装吗
It just feels a little weird winning for that article.
我只是觉得以这篇文章获奖很奇怪
- It just doesn't seem right. - What doesn't seem right?
- 不大对劲 - 哪不对劲？
Winning an award for an article called "Why the World Doesrt Need Superman."
这篇文章说世界不需要超人
When, according to this newspaper, they do.
可是所有的报纸上写的正好是相反
Lois, Pulitzer Prizes are like Academy Awards.
露意丝，普利兹奖就像奥斯卡奖
Nobody remembers what you got one for. It's just that you got one.
没人会记得你以什么作品得奖的 他们只会记得你得过奖
- But... - This is your night. You enjoy it.
- 但… - 今晚是属于你的，好好享受吧
I'm sure Kent's on the blackout.
肯特会写大停电的
Department of Water and Power, please.
请接水电部
7782, great.
7782，好的
Metropolis Public Works.
大都会工共设施部门
Hi, Stephen, Lois Lane from the Daily Planet. Blackout?
嗨，史帝芬 我是星球日报的露意丝莲恩
I just need a little info on a few outstanding power grids.
大停电？ 我只是想问一下电力分布图
Yeah, I do have it here, actually.
是的，我这里有
So the uptown grid went dark at 12:36 and midtown 10 seconds before.
所以住宅区在12:36时停电 商住宅区在那之前十秒停电
Which grid was hit first?
哪一区是最先停的？
It just reads Vanderwon'th.
在下林的附近
- Across the river? - 6 Springwood Drive.
- 河的对岸吗？ - 春木街6号
6 Springwood Drive. A residence or a business?
春木街6号，那是个商业还是住宅？
- Residence. - Sure? Nothing before that?
- 住宅 - 你确定吗？再之前就没有停电了？
- That's all it shows. - Thank you very much.
- 我确定 - 非常感谢
Oh, Jason.
糟糕，杰森
- There's your mom, Jason. - You're late, Mommy.
- 你妈妈来了 - 你迟到了，妈咪
Where are we? Is this the Pulitzer?
我们在哪里？ 这是普莉兹奖会场吗？
Nope. I've just gotta ask these people a few questions and then we can go.
不是，我只是要问这家人一些问题 马上就好了
Can I stay in the car?
我可以待在车子里吗？
No, honey.
不行，亲爱的
- Are we trespassing? - No. Yes.
- 我们这样算擅自闯入吗？ - 不算…算
Hello?
有人在吗？
I like the curly one.
我喜欢那顶
Let's go. This was a bad idea.
我们走，我们不该进来的
Lex Luthor.
雷克斯・路瑟
Lois Lane?
露意丝・莲恩？
You're bald.
你秃头
And what is your name?
你叫什么名字？
I'm not supposed to talk to strangers.
我不可以跟陌生人讲话
- Cute kid, and smart. - Thanks.
- 真可爱，又聪明 - 谢谢
We're not really strangers, are we? This is kind of a little reunion.
可是我们可不是陌生人喔 这应该可说是一个小重逢吧
Heck, I'm a fan.
我是你的仰慕者
I love your writing...
我喜欢你的作品
...and your dress. - I love your boat.
- 还有你的衣服 - 我喜欢你的船
How'd you get it? Swindle some widow out of her money?
你怎么弄来的？ 是不是又去骗哪个寡妇的钱？
That's funny. Didrt you win the Pulitzer Prize...
呵呵，真幽默 你不是得了普莉兹奖吗？
...for my favorite article of all time, " Why the World Doesrt Need Superman"?
题目是我最喜欢的 “为什么这世界不需要超人”
Didrt you have a few more years to go on that double life sentence?
你的双重无期徒刑不是还有 好几年牢要坐吗
Yes, well, we can thank the Man of Steel for that.
对呀，我该谢谢超人
I mean, he's really good at swooping in and catching the bad guys...
虽然他很会抓坏人
...but he's not so hot at the little things, like Miranda rights...
可是他对小事就不太内行
...due process, making your court date.
例如米兰达权利、正当法律程序 准时出庭作证等等
Did you have anything to do with the blackout?
你是不是跟大停电事件有关？
Are you fishing for an interview, Miss Lane?
你想要采访我吗，莲恩小姐？
It's been a while since you've been a headline.
你也好一阵子没出现在头版了
Maybe it's time people knew your name again.
也许人们应该再听听你的名字了
How about we turn this boat around, call a cab for my son...
不如我们把船折返回港 把我儿子送回家
...and then you can do whatever you want with me.
你想对我怎样都可以
No, I don't think we'll be turning around, Miss Lane...
我不会把船折回去的，莲恩小姐
...which means that we do have some time to kill.
所以我们有些时间可以闲聊
How about that interview?
来个采访怎么样啊？
Yeah, just call me if you hear anything. Okay. Thank you.
是的，有任何消息请打给我，谢谢
So, what did the school say?
学校说什么？
She picked him up at 3: 15.
她三点十五分就接走杰森了
- Hi, I heard about Lois. - Yes, come in, Clark, come in.
- 嗨，我听说露意丝的事了 - 进来，克拉克，进来
- Is there anything I can do? - Yeah, you're a reporter.
- 有什么我可以做的吗？ - 你是记者
- Help Richard track her down. - I'll check her computer.
- 帮理查把她找出来 - 我去看她的电脑
Excuse me, Clark.
不好意思，克拉克
What do you know about crystals?
你对水晶知道多少？
They make great chandeliers.
用水晶做的吊灯很漂亮
This crystal may seem unremarkable, but so is the seed of a redwood tree.
这块水晶看起来也许不起眼 不过我们那位穿紧身衣的朋友把它拿来
It's how our mutual friend in tights made his Arctic getaway spot.
建造他的北极渡假屋
Cute. It's a little small for my taste.
还蛮可爱的，但对我来说太小了
You're building an island?
你想建一座岛？
You're not seeing the big picture here, Miss Lane.
你要往更大的方面想，莲恩小姐
Let me enlarge it for you.
我帮你把它放大吧
Not just an island, an entirely new continent.
不只是一座岛，是一整个新大陆
An extinct world, reborn on our own.
从虚无制造出的新大陆
Why?
为什么？
Land, Miss Lane.
土地，莲恩小姐
I mean... Kitty, what did my father used to say to me?
咪咪，我父亲以前常对我说什么？
"You're losing your hair"?
你头发越来越稀疏了？
- Before that. - "Get out"?
- 在那之前 - 滚出去？
He said, " You can print money...
他说：钱可以印…
...manufacture diamonds, and people are a dime a dozen...
钻石可以制造 人类随手抓就一把
...but they'll always need land."
可是土地…我们永远需要土地
It's the one thing they're not making any more of.
土地是我们唯一无法制造出来的东西
But the United States...
可是美国…
Will be underwater.
美国会沉到海底
It's simple physics, Miss Lane.
这是很简单的物理学，莲恩小姐
Two objects cannot occupy the same space at the same time.
两件物体不能同时占据同一个空间
And the rest of the world will just let you keep it?
世界上其它人难道就会让你为所欲为吗？
- They'Il... - They'II...
- 他们会…
...what?
怎样？
I'll have advanced alien technology...
我将拥有…
...thousands of years beyond what anyone could throw at me.
比地球先进数千年的外星科技
Bring it on!
要打就来吧！
And eventually...
最后…
...the rest of the world will be begging me...
世界上的人会来求我
...for a piece of high-tech beachfront property.
给他们一块高科技的海滨土地
In fact, they'll pay through the nose for it.
事实上，他们会花大钱来跟我买
But millions of people will die.
可是数百万人会因此而死呀
Billions! Once again, the press underestimates me.
数十亿！ 媒体又一次低估了我
This is front-page news.
这可登上头版新闻了吧
Come on, let me hear you say it just once.
说吧，让我听你说一次，一次就好
- You're insane. - No! Not that. No, the other thing.
- 你是个疯子 - 不对，不是这句，另一句
It's dangling off the tip of your tongue. Let me hear it just once, please?
我知道你已经快脱口而出了 让我听吧，一次就好
- Superman will never... - Wrong!
- 超人绝不会让你… - 错！
What is that?
那是什么？
I think you know exactly what this is.
你应该知道这是什么
Mind over muscle, Miss Lane.
智力战胜武力，莲恩小姐
Mind...
智力
Who is that boy's father?
这小孩的父亲是谁？
Richard.
理查
Mr. Luthor, we're approaching the coordinates.
路瑟先生，我们已经接近目的座标了
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Yes, sir. Latitude 40 degrees north, longitude 73 degrees west.
是的，北纬40度西经73度
Don't let them leave this room.
别让他们离开这房间
Kitty, come with me. You're not gonna want to miss this.
咪咪，跟我来 你不会想错过这个的
- Damn it. - What?
- 可恶 - 怎么了？
She has a password.
她设了密码
"Jason."
杰森
"Richard."
理查
Try "Superman."
试试“超人”
"Superman." Great.
“超人”，太棒了
Don't touch that, honey.
别碰它
Why don't you go play the piano.
你去弹弹琴吧
Come on, come on, come on.
快点，快点，快点
Lex, this isn't like the train set.
雷克斯，这不像模型火车呀
I know.
我知道
Come on, come on.
快点，快点
Come on.
快点
- Honey, are you okay? - Yeah.
- 宝贝，你还好吗 - 还好
- Are you hurt? - I'm fine.
- 没受伤吧？ - 没有
Open this door! Open it!
开门！快开门！
Could you help Mommy open the door?
你能帮妈咪开这个门吗？
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's gonna be okay.
没事的
Okay? It's gonna be okay.
会没事的
We had a little problem downstairs.
楼下出了点小问题了
Brutus is dead.
布鲁斯死了
He got hit with the piano.
他被钢琴撞死的
Where's the boy?
那小孩呢？
With the mother, locked up in the pantry.
跟妈妈一起被关在食品储藏室
Oh, it's time for us to go.
是时间了，我们走
My camera's not working.
我相机出故障了
And my phone's not working.
手机也不行了
- Okay, I'm good. - That was weird.
- 我没事 - 真奇怪
Hey, guys. This just came through the fax.
伙计们，从传真过来的
It's Lois' handwriting, I'd recognize it anywhere.
这是露意丝的笔迹 我不会认错的
I just... No idea what the numbers mean.
我只是不知道这些号码是什么
- They're coordinates. - Coordinates.
- 那是坐标 - 坐标
That's just off the coast.
这就在出海不远处
Jimmy, tell Perry I'm taking the seaplane. Keep trying her cell.
吉米，告诉派瑞我把水上飞机开走了 还有，继续试她的手机
What are these, lottery numbers?
这是什么？乐透号码？
I think they're coordinates, chief.
我想他们是座标，主编
Chief...
主编…
Come on! Move it!
快点！走啊！
Chief!
主编
Great Caesar's ghost.
凯撒大帝的鬼魂
- Daddy. - Oh, my God.
- 爸爸 - 天啊
How did you get here?
你怎么来的？
I flew.
飞来的
Look out!
小心！
Mom!
妈妈！
Mom! Mom!
妈妈！妈妈！
Jason, come here! Jason!
杰森，过来！杰森！
Come here! Watch your head! Come here!
过来！小心头！过来！
Mommy! Mom!
妈妈！妈妈！
Jason!
杰森！
Jason, hold on!
杰森！坚持住！
- Have you got him? - I got him! Go!
- 拉住他了吗？ - 拉住了！
Hold on! Hold on!
坚持住！坚持住！
- Mommy! - Give him to me!
- 妈妈！ - 把他给我！
Mommy!
妈妈！
- Mommy! Mommy! - Come on, Jason! Come on!
- 妈妈！妈妈！ - 加油，杰森！加油！
- Lois! Lois! - Mommy!
- 露意丝！露意丝！ - 妈妈！
Jason, get on my back.
杰森，到我的背上来
Give me your hand.
把手给我
- Have you got them? - Yeah.
- 你抓紧他们了吗？ - 是的
Get buckled in!
快上去！
She'll be fine.
她会没事的
I can't take off in this.
我没办法在这种情况下起飞
- I'll point you in the right direction. - Thank you.
- 我可以推你一把 - 谢谢
See anything familiar?
有没有看到什么熟悉的东西？
I see an old mars sick joke.
我只看到一个老人的变态玩笑
Really? Because I see my new apartment...
是吗？我可是看到我的新公寓
...and a place for Kitty, one for my friends...
有咪咪的地方 还有我朋友的
...and that place over there, I'll rent out.
那边那个空间我准备租出去
But, you know, maybe you're right. You know, maybe it is a little cold.
也许你说的没错 也许这里是冷了点
It's... What's the word I'm searching for? It's a little...
应该怎么形容才好呢？
...alien.
这里有点“外星感”
It lacks that human touch.
好像少了点人性
You have something that belongs to me.
你拿走某样属于我的东西
Metropolis Tower, this is seaplane November-Seven-Two-Four-One-Hotel.
大都会塔台 这是水上飞机 N7241H 号
Do you copy?
请回答
Lois! Are you all right?
露意丝，你没事吧？
Yeah. What happened?
发生什么事了？
- Superman. - Where is he?
- 超人救了我们 - 他去哪了？
He went back.
他回去了
- Richard, we have to turn around. - What? No.
- 理查，我们要折回去 - 什么？不
- We have to turn around! - We barely made it out of there.
- 我们要回去那里！ - 我们好不容易才逃出来
- Now you want me to go back? - Yes, please!
- 你又要叫我飞回去？ - 是的，求求你
He'll die.
他会死的
All right, hold on.
好吧，抓紧
Kryptonite.
氪星
You're asking yourself, "How?"
你大概在想，“怎么会”
Didrt your dad ever teach you to look before you leap?
爸爸小时候难道没教过自己 要跳跃前先看清楚吗？
Crystals. They're amazing, aren't they?
水晶，它们真不可思议，不是吗？
They inerit the traits of the minerals around them...
它们将它们身边矿物质的特质变为己有
...kind of like a son ineriting the traits of his father!
就像儿子遗传爸爸的特质一样！
You took away five years of my life, I'm just returning the favor!
你从我生命中夺走好几年 我现在要报仇！
I'm still Superman!
我仍是超人！
Get up! Come on!
起来！
Now, fly.
飞吧
So long, Superman.
永别了，超人
Your leadership can stir others...
你的领导可影响人类
...to their own capacities for moral betterment.
动摇人心
The human heart is still subject to monstrous deceits.
人心仍受巨大谎言的影响
Our destruction could have been avoided. At this very moment...
我们的破坏要被制止 在这非常时刻…
...I could embrace you in my arms.
我把你拥入怀中
Your help would be called for endlessly. Remember me.
你的帮助是无尽的，记住我
Even for those tasks which human beings could solve themselves.
即使是那些人类能自己解决的问题
Remember me, Kal-EI.
记住我，凯尔
Remember me.
记住我
Supermars down there.
超人在那里
- You sure? - Yeah.
- 你确定？ - 是的
- Richard! - Yeah, I saw him. Strap in.
- 理查！ - 我看到他了，系好安全带
Lois!
露意丝！
Don't move.
别乱跑！
Come on, come on, come on.
快点！快点！快点！
Richard!
理查！
I'm trying! It's too choppy!
我在努力，浪太大了！
Oh, my God.
哦，天啊
How did you find me?
你们怎么找到我的？
Thank you.
谢谢
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
I have to go back.
我必须回去
You're hurt!
你已经受伤了！
Goodbye, Lois.
再见，露意丝
The technology on Krypton, Superman 's home world...
氪星，超人的家乡
...was based on manipulating the growth of crystals.
上面的科技是建立在操纵水晶上面的
Sounds like hocus-pocus to me.
听起来像在变魔术
Well, naturally, to the primitive mind, any sufficiently advanced technology...
对我们这些原始的脑袋来说
...would be indistinguishable from magic.
超先进的科技跟变魔术没什么两样
But imagine: Cities, vehicles, weapons...
但你想像一下： 城市、车辆，武器…
...entire continents, all grown.
整个大陆由此建立
Lex?
雷克斯？
Are billions of people really going to die?
真的有几亿人会死吗？
Yes.
是的
Lex, what's happening?
雷克斯，怎么回事？
Go, go, go. Get to the helicopter.
走走走，上直升机
Go! Out, out! Now!
快出去！
No, no, no, take nothing! Take nothing! Go, go!
不不不，什么也别拿，快走！
Got it.
好了
Here.
这里
- What did you do? - I'm sorry!
- 你做了什么？ - 对不起！
No!
不！
- What did you do? - I'm sorry!
- 你做了什么？ - 对不起！
Watch it.
看着点
- Clear a path. - Clear the way.
- 让路
- Move! - Trauma One.
- 快点！ - 1号急诊室
- Where we going? - Trauma One. Here it is.
- 去哪？
Watch it!
看着点
Got him!
好了！
Okay, I think I got it.
我想我搞定了
Penetrating side wound to right part of lower back.
刺穿的部位在后背右下部
No hemorrhage.
没有出血
Shock at 200.
200伏电击
Is that enough? He's not human.
够吗？他不是人类
All right, charge to three, 360.
好吧，充电到360伏
Clear!
好了！
It's kind of morbid, Perry.
这太悲观了，派瑞 [超人死了]
Always be prepared.
时刻做好准备
How is she?
她怎么样？
Thank you. Thanks, baby.
谢谢，谢谢宝贝
- Lois? - Yeah.
- 露意丝？ - 嗯
We can leave whenever you're ready.
你想离开的话我们随时可走
I mean...
我是说
...you don't have to be here.
你不需要留在这里
Where else would I be?
我还能去哪？
Police have surrounded the area in order to control thousands of visitors...
警察包围了那个区域
...who have arrived to show their support.
以便控制住数以千计的支持者
Many are carrying signs and banners...
很多人携带标语
I could drive.
我可以开车
- No official announcements over the past few hours...
过去几小时内无官方消息
...but unconfirmed reports from inside tell us...
但内部不确切的消息说
...the Man of Steel lies in a coma...
超人昏迷中
...his condition unchanged since he was admitted late yesterday.
自昨天情况一直没变
- Doctors have been vigilant in their... - Foreign exchange markets...
- 医生们一直密切观察 - 外汇市场…
- Where are you going? - To the hospital.
- 你们要去哪？ - 医院
I'd be careful down there, guys. It's a madhouse.
小心一点，那边一片混乱
- So much for parking. - Do you think I can get in?
- 看来连找停车位都省了 - 你想我进得去吗？
You're Lois Lane. They'll let you in.
你是露意丝・莲恩 他们会让你进去的
I wanna go with Mommy.
我要和妈妈去
Taxi.
计程车
I'll be right here.
我在这里等
Watch your head, okay? Here we go.
小心你的头 我们到了
This way, Miss Lane.
这边，莲恩小姐
Mommy? Is he gonna get better?
妈咪，他会好起来吗？
- I don't know. - I want him to.
- 我不知道 - 我想他好起来
I like him.
我喜欢他
Me too.
我也是
I don't know if you can hear me.
我不知道你听不听得到
They say sometimes that when people are...
听说当人们
That sometimes they can hear you.
他们能听见你说的话
I don't know if you can hear me.
我不知道你听不听得到
I wanted to tell you...
但我想告诉你…
Come on, honey.
走吧，宝贝
Step back, please!
请后退！
Lex, we only have six of those!
雷克斯，我们只有六颗椰子！
Six?
六颗？
I would trade 300,000 coconuts...
我愿意用三十万棵椰子
...and every ounce of your blood...
加上你体内所有的血液
...for a quart of gasoline!
来换取一罐汽油
But what will we have to eat?
可是我们要吃什么？
You will be different.
你将会与众不同
Sometimes, you will feel like an outcast.
有时候甚至会觉得自己被社会所被弃
But you'll never be alone.
但是你永远不是孤独的
You will make my strength your own.
你将拥有我的力量
You will see my life through your eyes...
你会透过你的眼睛看见我的一生
...as your life will be seen through mine.
就如我会透过我的眼睛看见你的一生
The son becomes the father...
儿子变成了父亲
...and the father becomes the son.
父亲又变成了儿子
Good night!
晚安！
L...
我…
Will we see you?
我们会…
Around?
再见到你吗？
I'm always around.
我一直都在
Good night, Lois.
晚安，露意丝